Register of the Wlodzimierz Wiskowski Collection, 1914-1919
Hoover Institution Archives
Wlodzimierz Wiskowski Collection,
1914-1919
27000
Wiskowski, Wlodzimierz
5 manuscript boxes 2.1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, reports, memoranda, booklets, leaflets, magazines, newspapers, memorials, and speeches, relating to political conditions in Poland during World War I, and the development of Polish nationalism
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1927.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Nationalism--Poland.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--History--German occupation, 1914-1918.
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1919
  - Austrian authorities in occupation of Poland, 1915 (Austriackie wladze okupacyjne) (Box 1.)
  - Central Agricultural Association (Poland), 1916 (Centralne Towarzystwo Rolnicze)
  - Central National Committee (Poland), 1915-1917 (Centralny Kimitet Narodowy)
  - City Council of Warsaw (Rada miejska), 1915-1917
  - Club of Polish Nationalists, 1915-1917 (Klub Panstwowcow Polskich)
  - Coordinating Committee of the Democratic Party of Poland, 1917 (Komisja Porozumiewawcza Stronnictw Demokratycznych)
    Extra file of position papers, and political leaflets. Polish leaflet collection file and duplicate newspapers.
  - Doyen Party Convention (Poland), 1915-1917 (Stronnictwo Konwentu Seniorow) (Box 2.)
  - Evangelic (Lutheran) Church in the Polish Kingdom, 1915-1917 (Ewangelicy w Krolestwie Polskim)
  - German authorities in occupation of Poland, 1914-1916 (Wladze okupacyjne niemieckie)
  - German authorities in occupation of Poland, 1916-1917 (Wladze okupacyjne niemieckie)
  - Jewish question in Poland, 1916-1917
  - League of Women (Poland), 1915-1917 (Liga Kobiet)
  - Lithuania, 1914-1917
  - Main Relief Council (Poland), 1916 (Rada Glowna Opiekuncza) (Box 3.)
  - Municipal Government and City Council in Poland, 1916-1917 (Zarzad Miejski i Rada Miejska)
  - National Center (Poland), 1917 (Centrum Narodowe)
  - National Inspectorate of the Legions (Poland), 1917 (Krajowy Inspektorat Legionow)
  - National Peasants Union (Poland), 1915-1917 (Narodowy Zwiazek Chlopski)
  - National Workers Union (Poland), 1915-1917 (Narodowy Zwiazek Robotniczy)
  - November the 5th of 1916, Declaration of an independent Polish Kingdom issued on this date
  - Organization of Polish Army, views by many different political parties, clubs and organizations, 1915-1919
  - Organizations of a new Polish army and government, views by many different political parties, clubs, and organizations, 1917 (Box 4.)
  - Party of Polish Democratic Politics, 1918 (Stronnictwo Polskiej Polityki Demokratycznej)
  - Polish education (Szkolnictwo polskie), 1915-1917
  - Polish Government
  - Polish Military Organization, 1915-1917 (Polska Organizacja Wojskowa)
  - Polish patriotic activities in Posen, Lithuania, and foreign countries, 1918
  - Polish Socialist Party (Polska Partia Socjalistyczna)
    - 1915-1917
    - 1918-1919 (Box 5.)
  - Polish Struggle for Independence, 1916
  - Provisional State Council of the Polish Kingdom, 1917 (Tymczasowa Rada Stanu Krolestwa polskiego)
  - Right Wing (Polish Conservatives, political parties and organizations), 1915-1917
  - Right Wing (Nationalist Conservative parties), 1918-1919